Guide to the Asa and Elna Spaulding Papers, 1909-1997 and undated, bulk 1935-1983 RL.01240
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Asa Spaulding Subgroup, 1909-1984 and undated, 331 boxes
  - Organizations Series, 1930-1983 and undated, bulk 1954-1970, 145 boxes
    - White Rock Baptist Church
      - Members,1979-1982 (Box AO-137)
      - Contributions,1966-1983 (Box AO-137)
      - Conventions,1942-1945 (Box AO-137)
      - Committees,1942-1982 (Box AO-137)
      - Correspondence,1937-1983, Folders 1-2 of 4 (Box AO-137)
      - Correspondence,1937-1983, Folders 3-4 of 4 (Box AO-138)
      - Finances,1948-1983 (Box AO-138)
      - Financial Corner,1962-1967 (Box AO-138)
      - Financial Statements,1939-1968 (Box AO-138)
      - Funeral Services,1965-1982 (Box AO-139)
      - Good Will Day,1963-1967 (Box AO-139)
      - Human Relations Institute,1967-1979 (Box AO-139)
      - Maud E. Logan District,1982-1983 (Box AO-139)
      - Miles Mark Fisher Scholarship Day,1973-1983 (Box AO-139)
      - Miles Mark Fisher Testimony,1963-1965 (Box AO-139)
      - Minutes of Trustee Meetings,1975-1980 (Box AO-139)
      - Miscellaneous,1937-1983 (Box AO-139)
      - Printed Material: A-Z,1958-1980 (Box AO-139)
      - Printed Material:Baptist Leader, 1976-1983, 3 folders (Box AO-139)
      - Printed Material:Baptist Leader (Spaulding's notes),1977-1983, 2 folders (Box AO-140)
      - Printed Material: Changed Lives,1980-1982 (Box AO-140)
      - Programs,1936-1983 (Box AO-140)
      - Programs (Sundays),1937-1938, 1954-1983, Folders 1-3 of 5 (Box AO-140)
      - Programs (Sundays),1937-1938, 1954-1983, Folders 4-5 of 5 (Box AO-141)
      - Reverend Lorenzo Lynch,1981-1982 (Box AO-141)
      - Race Relations Day,1964-1966 (Box AO-141)
      - Scholarship,1958-1960 (Box AO-141)
      - Sermons,1977-1979 (Box AO-141)
      - Special Committee,1966 (Box AO-141)
      - Sunday School,1940-1980 (Box AO-141)
      - Sunday School Lessons (Spaulding's notes,Adult Bible Quarterly),1976-1982, Folders 1-3 of 6 (Box AO-141)
      - Sunday School Lessons (Spaulding's notes,Adult Bible Quarterly),1976-1982, Folders 4-6 of 6 (Box AO-142)
      - Worship Plans,1953-1966 (Box AO-142)
    - Who's Who in America, 1975 (Box AO-142)
    - Wilmington Journal, 1978 (Box AO-142)
    - Women and Minority Directors Seminar, 1969-1974
      - Addresses and Writings,1973 (Box AO-142)
      - Clippings,1970-1974 (Box AO-142)
      - Correspondence,1973-1974, Folder 1 of 4 (Box AO-142)
      - Correspondence,1973-1974, Folders 2-4 of 4 (Box AO-143)
      - Miscellany,1973 (Box AO-143)
      - Printed Material,1969-1973 (Box AO-143)
      - Proceedings,1973-1974 (Box AO-144)
      - Publicity and News Releases,1973 (Box AO-144)
      - Questionnaires,1973 (Box AO-144)
    - Women-in-Action Coalition for the Prevention of Violence
      - Clippings,1968-1971 (Box AO-144)
      - Correspondence,1969 (Box AO-144)
      - Miscellany, undated (Box AO-144)
      - Printed Material,1968-1969 (Box AO-144)
      - Scrapbook, circa 1970 (Box AO-144)
    - World Affairs Center for the United States,1959-1960 and undated (Box AO-144)
    - World Food and Population Crisis Committee,1967 (Box AO-144)
    - WRAL-TV, undated (Box AO-144)
    - WTVD-TV,1970-1982 (Box AO-144)
    - York County Public Schools,1977 (Box AO-145)
    - Young Ideas, Inc.,1981 (Box AO-145)
    - Young Men's Christian Association,1961-1967 (Box AO-145)
    - Youth Fitness Commission of the N.C. Recreation Commission,1962 (Box AO-145)
    - Zeller's Limited and Subsidiary Companies,1968 (Box AO-145)
  - North Carolina Mutual Files Series, 1911-1979, bulk 1945-1979, 67 boxes
    Material documenting the full scope of the North Carolina Mutual Insurance Company's activities across more than half a century of its existence. A highlight of the series is the material relating to the groundbreaking and dedication of the company's new home office (1963-1966), a watershed event in the company's history. For this event, most material is filed under the heading "Dedication of Home Office Building," but some material also appears under "Home Office," a more general heading for materials about the operations of the company's Durham headquarters over a period of some forty years. Other major groups of material in the series are "Board Meetings" and "Reports" of various kinds, including actuarial reports and reports to policyholders. Folder titles are mainly topical subjects but may also include names of departments, individuals, and company publications. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Accounts, undated (Box NCM-1)
    - Accumulation Factors and Commutation Columns,1940-1941 (Box NCM-1)
    - Actuarial Department,1959-1967 (Box NCM-1)
    - Actuary,1933-1941 (Box NCM-1)
    - Addresses, 1932-1967 and undated (Box NCM-1)
    - Advertising,1965 (Box NCM-1)
    - African Visitors to the Home Office,1961-1967 (Box NCM-2)
    - Afro-American Life Insurance Co.,1941-1944 (Box NCM-2)
    - Agency Contracts, 1939-1945 and undated (Box NCM-2)
    - Agency Department,1957-1960, Folders 1-2 of 4 (Box NCM-2)
    - Agency Department,1957-1960, Folders 3-4 of 4 (Box NCM-3)
    - Agency Secretary,1964 (Box NCM-3)
    - Agency Officers,1964-1965 (Box NCM-3)
    - Agency Turnover,1964 (Box NCM-3)
    - Albany,1959-1963 (Box NCM-3)
    - Amendments,1941 (Box NCM-3)
    - American Life Convention, 4 folders (Box NCM-4)
    - Kwasi Amoaka-Atta, Deputy Governor of the Bank of Ghana,1962 (Box NCM-4)
    - Anniversary Luncheons,1959-1960 (Box NCM-4)
    - Annual Cloudburst Celebration,1960-1963, Folders 1-2 of 8 (Box NCM-4)
    - Annual Cloudburst Celebration,1960-1963, Folders 3-8 of 8 (Box NCM-5)
    - Annual Statement,1931-1981, Folders 1-3 of 34 (Box NCM-5)
    - Annual Statement,1931-1981, Folders 4-15 of 34 (Box NCM-6)
    - Annual Statement,1931-1981, Folders 16-26 of 34 (Box NCM-7)
    - Annual Statement,1931-1981, Folders 27-34 of 34 (Box NCM-8)
    - Assistant Agency Director,1961 (Box NCM-8)
    - Atlanta,1960-1963 (Box NCM-8)
    - Auditing Committee Minutes,1966-1967 (Box NCM-8)
    - Bankers Fire and Casualty Insurance Co.,1967-1968 (Box NCM-8)
    - Bargaining Committee,1962-1963 (Box NCM-9)
    - Bills Introduced to North Carolina General Assembly,1945 (Box NCM-9)
    - Birmingham,1959-1963 (Box NCM-9)
    - Board of Directors, 1937-1963 and undated (Box NCM-9)
    - Board Meetings,1927-1983, Folders 1-3 of 15 (Box NCM-9)
    - Board Meetings,1927-1983, Folders 4-9 of 15 (Box NCM-10)
    - Board Meetings,1927-1983, Folders 10-14 of 15 (Box NCM-11)
    - Board Meetings,1927-1983, Folder 15 of 15 (Box NCM-12)
    - Boards of Directors: Letters and Responses,1954-1955 (Box NCM-12)
    - Bond Portfolio,1941-1953 and undated (Box NCM-12)
    - Bonds and Stocks Owned,1958-1967 (Box NCM-12)
    - Branch Office,1962 (Box NCM-12)
    - Bryant, Victor S.,1946-1960 (Box NCM-12)
    - Budgets,1958-1967 (Box NCM-12)
    - Businessman's Special Policy, undated (Box NCM-12)
    - By-Laws,1929-1964 (Box NCM-12)
    - Cash Surrenders and Lapses 1962-1963 Mar., 2 folders (Box NCM-13)
    - Cashier Reporting Relationship Study,1966 (Box NCM-13)
    - Charleston,1959-1963 (Box NCM-13)
    - Charlotte,1958-1961 (Box NCM-13)
    - Chattanooga,1958-1962 (Box NCM-13)
    - Chicago Metropolitan Mutual Assurance Co.,1963-1968 (Box NCM-13)
    - Clement, W. A.,1966-1967 (Box NCM-13)
    - Clippings,1921-1949, 3 folders (Box NCM-14)
    - Columbia,1959-1962 (Box NCM-14)
    - Combination Agent's Agreement,1959 (Box NCM-14)
    - Commission Scales,1947 (Box NCM-14)
    - Company Colors,1963 (Box NCM-14)
    - Contest between North Carolina Mutual Washington District and Supreme,1962 (Box NCM-14)
    - Correspondence,1920-1982, Folders 1-3 of 37 (Box NCM-14)
    - Correspondence,1920-1982, Folders 4-9 of 37 (Box NCM-15)
    - Correspondence,1920-1982, Folders 10-17 of 37 (Box NCM-16)
    - Correspondence,1920-1982, Folders 18-24 of 37 (Box NCM-17)
    - Correspondence,1920-1982, Folders 25-29 of 37 (Box NCM-18)
    - Correspondence1920-1982, Folders 30-35 of 37 (Box NCM-19)
    - Correspondence1920-1982, Folders 36-37 of 37 (Box NCM-20)
    - Danville,1959-1960 (Box NCM-20)
    - Day, Aaron, Jr.,1959-1960 (Box NCM-20)
    - Death/Disability Claim Analyses,1942-1943 (Box NCM-20)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building
      - Addresses,1966, 2 folders (Box NCM-20)
      - Ceremonies and Guests1966 (Box NCM-20)
      - Clippings,1965-1966 (Box NCM-20)
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1964-1965 Aug. (Box NCM-20)
        - Form letter, 1965 July 26 (Box NCM-20)
        - Form letter, 1965 Aug. 3 (Box NCM-20)
        - General Correspondence, 1965 Sept. (Box NCM-20)
        - Form letter, 1965 Sept. 2 (Box NCM-20)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building (Box NCM-21)
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1965 Oct. (Box NCM-21)
        - Form letter, 1965 Oct. 14 (Box NCM-21)
        - General Correspondence, 1965 Nov., 2 folders (Box NCM-21)
        - Form letter, 1965 Nov. 17 (Box NCM-21)
        - General Correspondence, 1965 Dec. (Box NCM-21)
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Jan., 3 folders (Box NCM-21)
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Feb., Folders 1-3 of 7 (Box NCM-21)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building (Box NCM-22)
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Feb., Folders 4-7 of 7 (Box NCM-22)
        - Form letters, 1966 Feb. 4-28, 7 folders (Box NCM-22)
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Mar., Folders 1-2 of 10 (Box NCM-22)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building (Box NCM-23)
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Mar., Folders 3-10 of 10 (Box NCM-23)
        - Form letters, 1966 Mar. 4-10, 4 folders (Box NCM-23)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building (Box NCM-24)
      - Correspondence
        - General Correspondence, 1966 Apr. 1-29, 4 folders (Box NCM-24)
        - Form letters, 1966 Apr. 5-28, 5 folders (Box NCM-24)
        - General Correspondence, 1966 May -Oct. (Box NCM-24)
      - Dedication Committee,1965-1966 (Box NCM-24)
      - Printed Material,1964-1966, 2 folders (Box NCM-24)
    - Dedication of Home Office Building (Box NCM-25)
      - Guests and Participants,1966 (Box NCM-25)
    - Disability Premiums, undated (Box NCM-25)
    - District Offices, 1953-1967 and undated (Box NCM-25)
    - District Theatres Corporation,1946-1949 (Box NCM-25)
    - Dividends,1943-1967 (Box NCM-25)
    - Domestic Life Insurance Co.,1960-1961 (Box NCM-25)
    - Dumas, Alexander P.,1959-1962 (Box NCM-25)
    - Durham,1959-1962 (Box NCM-26)
    - East Baltimore,1959-1962 (Box NCM-26)
    - Endorsements, undated (Box NCM-26)
    - Executive Committee,1932-1975 (Box NCM-26)
    - Executive Vice President, Form letter, 1962 Nov. 13 (Box NCM-26)
    - Field Bulletin Index: Book No. 1 (1-252), Book No. 2 (253-278),1922-1961 (Box NCM-26)
    - Field Committee,1933-1963, Folders 1-3 of 7 (Box NCM-26)
    - Field Committee,1933-1963, Folders 4-7 of 7 (Box NCM-27)
    - Field Compensation Study Committee,1962 (Box NCM-27)
    - Field Operations, 1959, 5 folders (Box NCM-27)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary,1949 (Box NCM-27)
    - Figure Sheets and Calculations, undated (Box NCM-27)
    - Finance Committee,1967-1975 (Box NCM-27)
    - Financial,1949-1954, 2 folders (Box NCM-28)
    - Financial Statements (Monthly),1958-1960, 4 folders (Box NCM-28)
    - Financial Studies and Analyses,1943 (Box NCM-28)
    - Forms Being Drafted, 1933-1935 and undated, Folder 1 of 2 (Box NCM-28)
    - Forms Being Drafted,1933-1935 and undated, Folder 2 of 2 (Box NCM-29)
    - L. B. Frasier, Agency Secretary,1959 (Box NCM-29)
    - Thad B. Galliard, C. L. U.,1963 (Box NCM-29)
    - Gibraltar Mutual Life Insurance Co.,1943-1944 (Box NCM-29)
    - W. M. Gilliam,1961-1962 (Box NCM-29)
    - Goldsboro,1958-1963 (Box NCM-29)
    - Goldshield Laundries Group Insurance Project, 1940-1944 and undated (Box NCM-29)
    - Great Lakes Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1942-1945 and undated (Box NCM-29)
    - Greensboro,1959-1963 (Box NCM-29)
    - Gregg, N. L., Assistant Agency Director,1962-1963 (Box NCM-29)
    - Group Insurance,1922-1941, 3 folders (Box NCM-29)
    - Guertin Bill,1938-1946 (Box NCM-30)
    - Health and Accidents Benefits,1943 (Box NCM-30)
    - History Committee,1966 (Box NCM-30)
    - Holly Knoll Associates,1947-1961 (Box NCM-30)
    - Home Development,1938-1946 (Box NCM-30)
    - Home Office
      - Attendance,1959-1967 (Box NCM-30)
      - Bulletins,1924-1963, 2 folders (Box NCM-30)
      - Departments,1959-1963 (Box NCM-30)
      - Directories,1964-1967 (Box NCM-30)
      - Forums,1955-1966 (Box NCM-30)
      - Groundbreaking, 1963 Jan.-Apr. 23, 2 folders (Box NCM-30)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-31)
      - Groundbreaking, 1966 May 20-31, 4 folders (Box NCM-31)
      - Home Office Committee,1951-1963, 2 folders (Box NCM-31)
      - Home Office Operations Meetings,1964-1967 (Box NCM-31)
      - Home Office Manual,1965 (Box NCM-31)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-32)
      - Memoranda,1930-1934, 8 folders (Box NCM-32)
      - Miscellany, 1930-1959 and undated, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box NCM-32)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-33)
      - Miscellany,1930-1959 and undated, Folder 3 of 3 (Box NCM-33)
      - New Building, 1960-1967 and undated, Folders 1-4 of 17 (Box NCM-33)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-34)
      - New Building, 1960-1967 and undated, Folders 5-10 of 17 (Box NCM-34)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-35)
      - New Building,1960-1967 and undated, Folders 11-16 of 17 (Box NCM-35)
    - Home Office (Box NCM-36)
      - New Building,1960-1967 and undated, Folder 17 of 17 (Box NCM-36)
      - New Building: Proposals and Correspondence,1956 (Box NCM-36)
      - New Building: Purchase of Four Acres. Correspondence and Clippings,1960, 2 folders (Box NCM-36)
      - Organization Surveys,1963 (Box NCM-36)
      - Operations Staff,1965 (Box NCM-36)
      - Personnel,1948-1966 (Box NCM-36)
      - Printed Material,1964-1966 (Box NCM-36)
      - Programs,1957-1963 (Box NCM-36)
    - Home Office
      - Reports, Surveys,1962, 2 folders (Box NCM-37)
      - Salaries,1943-1955 (Box NCM-37)
      - Time Clock,1963 (Box NCM-37)
      - Training Programs,1961-1967 (Box NCM-37)
      - Visitors,1960-1964 (Box NCM-37)
    - The Hotline. Home Office Newsletter.1977-1983 (Box NCM-37)
    - IBM (International Business Machines Corporation),1955 (Box NCM-38)
    - Income Tax Matters,1951 (Box NCM-38)
    - Increase and Decrease Statements,1960-1963 (Box NCM-38)
    - Index to A. T. Spaulding's Files, undated (Box NCM-38)
    - Industrial Credit Plan,1964 (Box NCM-38)
    - Industrial Debit Growth Drive, 1964 Oct. 2-15, 3 folders (Box NCM-38)
    - Industrial Life Insurance Co.,1945 (Box NCM-39)
    - Industrial Policies, undated (Box NCM-39)
    - Industrial Study of Production,1963 (Box NCM-39)
    - Installment Tables,1940-1942 (Box NCM-39)
    - Insurance Legislation โ State of North Carolina,1945 (Box NCM-39)
    - Interest Basis (2 1/2 %) on Policies,1942-1944 (Box NCM-39)
    - Inventory of Industrial Policies,1944-1946 (Box NCM-39)
    - Jackson Funeral System Association,1944-1946 (Box NCM-39)
    - Job Evaluation Committee,1962-1963 (Box NCM-39)
    - Jobbers' Pants Factory,1935-1941 (Box NCM-39)
    - Jolaoso, Olumiji,Ambassador of Nigeria,1978 (Box NCM-39)
    - Kennedy, W. J., Jr.,1937-1944 (Box NCM-39)
    - Keynote Address Material,1949-1959, 2 folders (Box NCM-39)
    - Lapsed Ordinary Policies, 1959-1963 July, 2 folders (Box NCM-40)
    - Letters to Key People Who Are Not Policyholders,1963 (Box NCM-40)
    - Life and Casualty Insurance Co. of Tennessee,1950 (Box NCM-40)
    - Life Office Management Association Exams,1965 (Box NCM-40)
    - Long Range Planning for Development of Parrish St. and Orange St. Properties,1962 (Box NCM-40)
    - Looking Ahead Program,1961 (Box NCM-40)
    - Los Angeles, 1961, 2 folders (Box NCM-40)
    - Louisiana Industrial Life Insurance Co.,1944-1948, 2 folders (Box NCM-40)
    - Luncheons,1963-1964, 3 folders (Box NCM-41)
    - Mailing Lists,1956-1959 (Box NCM-41)
    - Management Consultant Proposals,1957-1963, 2 folders (Box NCM-41)
    - Management of Profits,1963 (Box NCM-41)
    - Managers Advisory Council, 1958-1965 and undated (Box NCM-41)
    - Managers' and Assistant Managers' Compensation, 1941-1946 and undated (Box NCM-42)
    - Managers' Institutes,1936-1938 (Box NCM-42)
    - Marvin, Murray J.,1965-1969 (Box NCM-42)
    - Matchbook Cover Series: Prominent Black Americans, undated (Box NCM-42)
    - Maynard, H. B. and Co.,1964 (Box NCM-42)
    - McDougald, R. L.,1943 (Box NCM-42)
    - MDO Study Committee,1962 (Box NCM-42)
    - Memoranda,1956-1983 (Box NCM-42)
    - Memorial Recreation Forest, Inc.,1962 (Box NCM-42)
    - Memphis,1958-1963 (Box NCM-42)
    - Menke and Company,1965-1967 (Box NCM-42)
    - Merrick-Moore Memorial Scholarship Fund,1943 (Box NCM-42)
    - Merrick-Moore-Spaulding Award,1966-1967 (Box NCM-42)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co.,1952-1958 (Box NCM-42)
    - Montgomery,1963 (Box NCM-43)
    - Moody's Investors Service, 1949-1961, 2 folders (Box NCM-43)
    - Moody's Investors Service: Appraisal of Securities for North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Co.,1945-1954, 2 folders (Box NCM-43)
    - Bernard Moore, Sr., 1952-1961 and undated (Box NCM-44)
    - Mortality Bonuses, 1917-1944 and undated (Box NCM-44)
    - Mortality Tables and Experiences, undated (Box NCM-44)
    - Mortgage Loan and Real Estate Committee,1960-1963, 2 folders (Box NCM-44)
    - The Mutual, 1927 (Box NCM-44)
    - Nashville,1959-1961 (Box NCM-45)
    - Negro-Operated Business Institutions, Durham, NC,1962 (Box NCM-45)
    - New Sick Benefit Policy,1932 (Box NCM-45)
    - New York and Washington Visits,1965 (Box NCM-45)
    - Newark, NJ,1958-1963 (Box NCM-45)
    - Newport News,1959-1963 (Box NCM-45)
    - News Releases, 1957-1963 June, 4 folders (Box NCM-45)
    - Newsorama,1961-1963 (Box NCM-46)
    - Norfolk,1959-1962 (Box NCM-46)
    - Northern Frontier Planning Committee, 1958-1962 and undated (Box NCM-46)
    - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company,1953-1956 (Box NCM-46)
    - Not Taken Charges,1963 (Box NCM-46)
    - O'Toole Associates,1962 (Box NCM-46)
    - Official Staff Meetings,1962-1965 (Box NCM-46)
    - Office Space,1970 (Box NCM-46)
    - Optional Mode of Settlement,1944 (Box NCM-46)
    - Ordinary School-Study Outline,1962 (Box NCM-46)
    - Organization Survey,1962 (Box NCM-46)
    - Organizational Structure,1946 (Box NCM-46)
    - Overseas Applicants,1962 (Box NCM-46)
    - Pension Plans, 1944-1948 and undated (Box NCM-46)
    - Pension Trusts,1943 (Box NCM-47)
    - Personal Income Per Capita,1961 (Box NCM-47)
    - Personnel Staff,1960-1963 (Box NCM-47)
    - Philadelphia,1947-1963 (Box NCM-47)
    - Pittsburgh,1952-1963 (Box NCM-47)
    - Planning Committees,1959-1963 (Box NCM-47)
    - Policies (specimens),1930-1941, Folders 1-5 of 11 (Box NCM-48)
    - Policies (specimens),1930-1941, Folders 6-11 of 11 (Box NCM-49)
    - Policy and Objectives of the Company,1963-1968 (Box NCM-50)
    - Policyholders' Meetings, 1948-1968 and undated (Box NCM-50)
    - Premiums, 1939-1943 and undated (Box NCM-50)
    - President's Club Convention, 1964-1965 and undated (Box NCM-50)
    - President's Reception,1962 (Box NCM-50)
    - Presidential Cruise,1960-1961 (Box NCM-50)
    - Printed Material,1925-1982, Folder 1 of 9 (Box NCM-50)
    - Printed Material,1925-1982, Folders 2-7 of 9 (Box NCM-51)
    - Printed Material,1925-1982, Folders 8-9 of 9 (Box NCM-52)
    - Procedural Manual, 1963 and undated (Box NCM-52)
    - Proposals, 1961, 3 folders (Box NCM-52)
    - Proposed New Group Insurance Policy,1951-1956 (Box NCM-52)
    - Publication Committee,1960 (Box NCM-52)
    - Questionnaires,1934-1937, 5 folders (Box NCM-53)
    - Raleigh,1959-1961 (Box NCM-54)
    - Rating Chart for Districts,1945 (Box NCM-54)
    - Real Estate Department,1947 (Box NCM-54)
    - Reception,1965 (Box NCM-54)
    - Reinsurance,1947 (Box NCM-54)
    - Reports and Statements,1937-1958, 3 folders (Box NCM-54)
    - Reports of Actuary,1933-1955, Folders 1-3 of 9 (Box NCM-54)
    - Reports of Actuary,1933-1955, Folders 4-9 of 9 (Box NCM-55)
    - Reports of the Controller,1966-1969, 2 folders (Box NCM-56)
    - Reports of the Real Estate Department,1939-1941, 2 folders (Box NCM-56)
    - Reports on Examination,1932-1965, Folders 1-3 of 10 (Box NCM-56)
    - Reports on Examination,1932-1965, Folders 4-9 of 10 (Box NCM-57)
    - Reports on Examination,1932-1965, Folder 10 of 10 (Box NCM-58)
    - Reports to Policyholders,1960-1967, Folders 1-4 of 6 (Box NCM-58)
    - Reports to Policyholders,1960-1967, Folders 5-6 of 6 (Box NCM-59)
    - Retirement,1944-1945, 2 folders (Box NCM-59)
    - Reserves, 1911-1940 and undated, 2 folders (Box NCM-59)
    - The Review(formerly The Weekly Review), 1947-1982 Mar., Folder 1 of 9 (Box NCM-59)
    - The Review(formerly The Weekly Review),1947-1982, Folders 2-7 of 9 (Box NCM-60)
    - The Review(formerly The Weekly Review),1947-1982, Folders 8-9 of 9 (Box NCM-61)
    - Richmond,1959-1963 (Box NCM-61)
    - Roanoke,1959-1963 (Box NCM-61)
    - Salaries, 1941-1945 and undated (Box NCM-61)
    - Salary and Employee Benefits Committee,1973 (Box NCM-61)
    - Sales Book, circa 1966 (Box NCM-61)
    - Sales Training Seminar,1963 (Box NCM-61)
    - Savannah,1959-1963 (Box NCM-61)
    - Schools, 1950-1958 and undated (Box NCM-61)
    - Securities Investment File,1958-1967 (Box NCM-61)
    - Sell-E-Bration,1962 (Box NCM-62)
    - Seminars โ Field Clerical Personnel,1960 (Box NCM-62)
    - Sick Claims,1958-1962 (Box NCM-62)
    - Sixtieth Anniversary Celebration
      - Part 1: Planning and Invitations, 1958-1959 Mar. (Box NCM-62)
      - Part 2: Responses, 1959 Feb.-Apr. (Box NCM-62)
      - Part 3: Congratulations and Thank Yous, 1959 Apr.-Nov. (Box NCM-62)
    - Sloan, M. A.,1960-1962 (Box NCM-62)
    - Southeastern Planning Committee,1961-1962 (Box NCM-62)
    - Southern Railway System,1948-1959 (Box NCM-62)
    - Spartanburg,1959-1963 (Box NCM-62)
    - Spaulding, Asa T.Portraits at work,1959 and undated (Box NCM-63)
    - Spaulding, C. C.,1943 (Box NCM-63)
    - Spears, A. E.,1955-1961 (Box NCM-63)
    - Specimen Letters,1962 (Box NCM-63)
    - Staff Managers' School,1963-1965 (Box NCM-63)
    - Statistical Bulletin,1923 (Box NCM-63)
    - Stromberg-Carlson,1963 (Box NCM-63)
    - Supervisory Training Book,1964 (Box NCM-63)
    - Supplementary Contracts, 1944 and undated (Box NCM-63)
    - Survey, 1924-1942 and undated (Box NCM-63)
    - Tax Relief,1945 (Box NCM-63)
    - Teachers' Disability and Retirement Association, undated (Box NCM-63)
    - Telegrams,1960-1961 (Box NCM-63)
    - Telephone Expenses,1962 (Box NCM-63)
    - Thanksgiving Message,1963 (Box NCM-63)
    - Thriftmaster Policy,1959 (Box NCM-63)
    - Time Capsule,1963 (Box NCM-63)
    - Toure, Sekou,President of Guinea,1959 (Box NCM-63)
    - Tours of the Home Office,1945-1966 (Box NCM-64)
    - Training Manuals,1962 (Box NCM-64)
    - Transfer Practices of Other Companies,1943 (Box NCM-64)
    - Unity Mutual Division,1960-1962, 2 folders (Box NCM-64)
    - Unpaid Ordinary Lapsed Matured Endowments,1962 (Box NCM-64)
    - Visiting Groups,1962 (Box NCM-64)
    - Volume, undated (Box NCM-65)
    - Vouchers,1941-1946 (Box NCM-65)
    - War Risk and Aviation Exclusion Provision,1940-1944 (Box NCM-65)
    - Washington,1950-1963 (Box NCM-65)
    - Watts, C. D.,1951-1963 (Box NCM-65)
    - The Weekly Underwriter, 1945-1957 (Box NCM-65)
    - West Baltimore,1961 (Box NCM-65)
    - West Philadelphia,1959-1961 (Box NCM-65)
    - West Publishing Co.,1956 (Box NCM-65)
    - The Whetstone. Correspondence and Material for Articles, 1952-1968 and undated (Box NCM-66)
    - The Whetstone. Issues, 1932-1960, Folders 1-6 of 9 (Box NCM-66)